# NIKUNJ SATHAWARA

### FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

+91 97247 99165

nikunj.1947@gmail.com



B/5 Smurti-Row-House, Nigam Road, Ghodasar, Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

### **ABOUT ME**

Self-motivated web developer with more than 5+ years of experience of working on various projects of different industries on frameworks like ReactJs, Nodejs, Laravel, Lumen, CI and jQuery. Passionate and hardworking with penchant for meeting deadlines. Interested in role with company promoting best practices and offering diverse client projects.

### **EXPERIENCE**

### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Bacancy Technology, Ahmedabad | December 2020 - Current

- Worked as full-stack developer in JavaScript (jQuery, ReactJs, Nodejs) and PHP (Laravel) technologies.
- Working with Agile methodology.
- Task designing as per client requirement.
- Client Communication and give weekly update to client in weekly meeting.
- Work In a Team so deliver best product to client and share and improve knowledge.

### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER L1**

IndiaNIC, Ahmedabad | August 2019 - November 2020

- Mostly involved in Laravel/Lumen web applications.
- Integration of any tool/API including third party libraries.
- Lead the team and manage sprint planning.
- Helped other developers in various R&D tasks.
- -Tested websites with test cases prior to deployment

### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Wama Software, Ahmedabad | December 2016 - July 2019

- Worked as full-stack developer in PHP (Laravel, Lumen, Codelgniter) and JavaScript (jQuery, ReactJs) technologies.
- Regularly update the knowledge of latest industry trends in web development and related technologies.
- Tested websites with test cases prior to deployment.

### SKILLS

### **PROFESSIONAL**

- Web Development
- Problem Solver
- Team Management
- Positive Approach
- Communication Skills
- Collaborative Nature

### PERSONAL

- Creative Spirit
- Reliable & Professional
- Time Management
- Team Player
- Quick Learner
- Always Motivated

### **EXPERTISE**

- Fields :- Web Development, Rest API for Web Application and Mobile Apps
- Technologies :- JavaScript And PHP
- Frameworks/CMS :- ReactJs, NodeJs, Laravel, Lumen, Cl, JQuery,
- Databases :- MySQL and MongoDB
- Project Management Tools :- Bitbucket, Github, Gitlab, JIRA and Slack
- Development Tools :- NetBeans, VS Code, Sublime, MySQL WorkBench etc.

### **EDUCATION**

## BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (COMPUTER APPLICATION & INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY)

K S School of Business Management | 2012-2015

## MASTER OF SCIENCE (COMPUTER APPLICATION & INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY)

K S School of Business Management | 2015-2017

### **PROJECTS**

#### **CALLONDOC**

Get an online doctor visit anytime from anywhere when you need one from CallOnDoc. There is no wait to get an online doctor appointment today. It provide features like primary care services from the comfort of your home and also provides e-prescription for minor illnesses and pre-existing conditions.

### ILIFE

IILife is a online insurance portal for life insurance agents to brand a microsite, provide quotes in real time, and access CRM functionalities all in one place.

#### **TAXBOTIC**

Taxbotic is a workflow management software that automates document requests and workflows for T1 clients of accounting professional.

### **LABORNET**

LaborNet was developed to solve this problem by being an industry centralized database that allows moving companies and drivers to search for labourers by the city, state or zip code and post jobs for labourers to find and apply for. The capability to actively search for labourers as well as post jobs truly streamline the process unlike anything else.

### **DATEMYFRIEND**

The DateMyFriend format was created to deliver a new approach to online dating in Australia. It introduces you to other great singles through the eyes of friends. It is focused on giving you a great platform for meeting like minded singles. Everyone on the site has been described by their friends so you know you're getting genuine reviews.

### AND MANY MORE...

- Bella Pizza A pizza ordering system with paypal payment gateway.
- **Primetime** An event management system for Artists and Musicians.
- Townwall- A website is a place to discover upcoming events and services.
- Marmosque A website will present you with your daily matches. you can ask the imam for advice, guidance or facilitation.
- **Tallyfy** Tallyfy is the only workflow and process management software that gives you everything you need to automate tasks, document processes, track workflows and run training in a single system.

### INTERESTS

- Challenging Tasks
- Traveling, Music
- Learn New Things like Crypto-currency
- Explore IoT, ML and AI